Daniel Wierdsma

 ♥ Burlington, Ontario, Canada
 ■ dan.wierdsma@gmail.com

1 +1 (519) 635 4151

Professional Summary

Site Reliability Engineer with five years' experience building large-scale infrastructures designed to handle millions of users using container orchestration tools; launched Covid test and vaccination forms used by over 5 million unique users; became quickest team member to join on-call rotation after only 3 weeks.

Work Experience

Site Reliability Engineer II | Mattermost

May 2022 to May 2023

- Maintained over 15,000 production Mattermost workspaces in 6 Kubernetes clusters with 99.9% uptime
- O Led team to create a highly scalable and cost-effective deployment solution for the company's Kubernetes services; leveraging over 150 ArgoCD Applications
- O Developed **Helm Charts** used by 5+ development teams, promoting GitOps way of managing services and increasing code delivery efficiency by 20%
- O Deployed, maintained, and upgraded Mattermost Operator across 5 Kubernetes clusters, automating workspace creation and deletion, saving over 10 hours per week
- Implemented cost cutting procedures across AWS accounts to Mattermost Cloud; cutting spending by 40%
- O Collaborated with Calls team to build a cloud-native version of Mattermost Calls Recorder, resulting in improved scalability, reliability, and performance; **reduced cost by 50**%
- Responded to high-priority system incidents and outages during weekly on-call rotations, **improving system** availability by 15%

DevOps Engineer | Daylight

May 2020 to May 2022

- O Orchestrated the migration of AWS ECS services to Azure AKS for all Daylight environments; designed to decreased infrastructure costs by 10% and improved scalability by 30%
- O Launched Shoppers Drug Mart COVID-19 testing and vaccination forms to over 5 million users
- O Revamped existing CloudFormation Troposphere scripts using Terraform, cutting down new environment setup time by 80%
- O Led yearly SOC 2 Type 2 audits for 2 years, collaborating with internal auditors to review and improve controls

 DevOps Engineer | Tulip Retail

 January 2019 to April 2020
 - O Developed SFTP Automation Framework leveraging AWS services to reduce client onboarding time by 50%
 - O Engineered and deployed CI/CD frameworks for 10+ serverless applications; utilized GitLab CI to automatically test and deploy new changes, reducing deployment time by 60%
 - O Implemented a new monitoring solution that leveraged Prometheus, Thanos, Grafana, and Alertmanager

Conference Speaker | AWS Summit Toronto

October 2019

Managed a cross-team effort that leveraged AWS services (Transfer for AWS, Lambdas, DynamoDB, SQS) to create a custom SFTP Automation solution that eliminated the need for manual setup of Virtual Machine instances; presented solution at AWS Summit Toronto 2019, reducing customer setup time from 2 weeks to 1.

Development Experience

* Kubernetes, Terraform, ArgoCD, Docker, Cloudflare, Packer, Helm, kOps, Teleport, KinD

· Prometheus, Thanos, Grafana, Loki, Tempo, Istio, GitLab CI, Github Actions, NGINX, Bash, Git

AWS (5+ years), Azure (2+ years), GCP (2+ years), Amazon Linux, Ubuntu, Debian, macOS

■ Back End • Python, Go, Node.js, PHP

Databases
• RDS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, CloudSQL, DynamoDB, Redis

Fundamentals · Cloud, GitOps, Microservices, CI/CD, Serverless Applications, Agile Development

Education

University of Waterloo December 2018